Brian Shipos

2405 NE 113th Street #5, Seattle, WA 98125 | 804.938.9903 | bshipos@gmail.com | www.bshipos.com

OBJECTIVE

Utilize my ability to adapt to fast changing priorities and quickly master new tasks to switch careers into the programming field as a Front-end Developer. I have a Bachelor of Science degree in Graphic Design and 14+ years working in an environment with competing deadlines and a focus on collaboration to achieve goals.

SKILLS

Javascript (...ES9) HTML5 Python 3

React CSS3 Adobe Creative Suite VCS (Git) PostgreSQL Microsoft Office

EXPERIENCE

RECENT PROJECTS - WWW.GITHUB.COM/DEMIURGIS

- Facial Recognition Project A responsive React App that recognizes the presence of a face in a photograph.
 Utilizes a REST server API with Express and Node.js. Registration and Sign-In utilizes a PostgreSQL database.
 API for facial recognition provided by Clarifai API. Active page: facial-recognition-shipos.herokuapp.com
- Cat Friends Project A responsive React App that sorts a contact list. Created with React and then refactored with Redux. Active page: demiurgis.github.io/cat-friends/
- Background Generator Simple app that displays a linear gradient as background. Color selectors and a random feature allows for custom backgrounds with CSS dynamic text. – Active page: demiurgis.github.io/background-generator/

STORE MANAGER | FEDEX OFFICE AND PRINT CENTER | 9/2008 - 11/2018

- · Promoted to Senior Store Manager 6/2018
- Fostering communication, teamwork, and unity among the team that allows for sharing of ideas and positions yet celebrates diversity and different viewpoints.
- · Monitoring metrics, forecasting, and business practices to adhere to company expectations and goals.
- Performing sales calls with new and existing clients to foster revenue growth and repeat business.
- · Maintaining schedules, payroll, and approval of time worked.
- Working with Human Resources to recruit, interview, select, and hire new employees.
- · Working closely with clients in order to foster a positive image of the company and provide excellent service.

FEDEX KINKO'S | 02/2004-09/2008

- · Production Operator -> Senior Project Coordinator -> Assistant Manager
- · Operation of machines and running production to ensure jobs are completed on time and correctly.
- Provide leadership for the shift, prioritize, and manage projects from order entry to delivery.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE | 2000-2003 | ART INSTITUTE OF PITTSBURGH

- · Major: Graphic Design.
- Awarded the Dean's Award at graduation with a 3.7 grade point average.
 Courses focused on a variety of technical art experience, including web design and Html, as well as a selection of fine art skills.